A Guide to the Downtown-Lower Manhattan Association, Inc. records FA085
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Alliance for Downtown New York, Inc. (Downtown-Lower Manhattan Business Improvement District), 1975-1995, bulk 1993-1995; 1993-1995; 3; 2.925 Cubic Feet 9 document cases
  - Alliance for Downtown New York - Marketing, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 2066)
  - Alliance for Downtown New York - Tickler File, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 2067)
    Transportation
  - Alliance for Downtown New York - Transportation, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 2068)
  - Alliance for Downtown New York - 55 Water Street, 1994 (Box 235, Folder 2069)
- Downtown Lower Manhattan Association photographs, 1937-1995; 1081; 7 Cubic Feet 16 manuscript boxes (approximately 1100 prints and 900 slides)
  Downtown Lower Manhattan Association
  - Photographs Removed from the Archival Collection, 1
    - Planning Committee - Meeting, September 5, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sanitation - Anti-Litter Task Force - Project Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Directors - Committeepersons - Officers - Biographical Files, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Directors - Committeepersons - Officers, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Directors - Committeepersons - Officers, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Directors - Committeepersons - Officers, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - William Randolph Hearst Commemorative Medals of Award Dinner (Ninth Annual) - "The New Look Downtown", April 15, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - San Francisco Planning and Urban Renewal Association - First Annual Meeting - "Urban Renewal: The Problem of the Central City", January 24, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Breakfast Meetings - General, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Breakfast Meeting, December 14, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Breakfast Meeting, January 17, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Breakfast Meeting, April 18, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Breakfast Meeting, May 14, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Breakfast Meeting, June 11, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Breakfast Meeting, January 14, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Member Mailings, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Adopt-A-Station, 1976-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - American Merchant Mariners' Memorial, Inc., 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Assay Office, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Battery Park City, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Battery Park City, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Battery Park City, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Bicentennial, New York City - Brochures, etc., 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bicentennial/1989 Activities, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Bowling Green Park - Christmas Tree, 1983-1988, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Brooklyn Bridge Southwest, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Brooklyn Bridge Southwest, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bus Shelters, 1975, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Chambers - Canal Civic Association, 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1962-1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Civic Center (New York), 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Convention Center (Jacob K. Javits), 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Convention Center - Photos (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Convention Center - Press Kit, May 5, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - The Douglass Leigh Organizations, Inc., 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Downtown Sites (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Ellis Island, 1963-1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Ellis Island, 1984-1993 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of New York, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Ferry Service, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Fountains, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Hearst Dinner - General, September-November 1961 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Hearst Dinner - Photos, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Historic Sites Committee, 1966-1967, 1991, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - History (Downtown Manhattan), 1971-1991 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Holocaust Museum, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Hotels - Hotel Millennium, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Hydrofoil, 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Landmarks, 1962-February 1965 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Landmarks, November 1966-December 1967 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Legion Memorial Square (Louise Nevelson Plaza), 1978-1987 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Legion Memorial Square (Louise Nevelson Plaza), 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Liberty Plaza, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Lower Manhattan Marketing Association (LOMA), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Lower Manhattan Project - Vital Records (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Manhattan Landing, March-April 1972 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Newstands, 1970-1994 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - New York Stock Exchange, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - New York Stock Exchange, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Peddlers, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Peddlers, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Plaque - Federal Hall - Wall Street, October 10, 1961, 1961-1970 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Port of New York Authority, 1964-1966 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Port of New York Authority, 1968-1972 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - PATH - Port Authority Trans-Hudson, 1965-1979 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - South Street Seaport, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Staggered Work Hours, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Traffic and Transportation - Parking, Street Signs, Pedestrian Crossings, etc., 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Trolley Cars, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Wall Street Subway Station (Lexington Avenue) - Refurbishing, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Wall Street Subway Station (Lexington Avenue) - Refurbishing, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - World Trade Center - Reports and Proposals, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - D-LMA, Inc. "Second Report", November 1963 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - D-LMA, Inc. "Second Report" - Presentation of Second Report by David Rockefeller at City Hall, November 20, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - D-LMA, Inc. Tenth Anniversary Meeting and Brochure, June 10, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - D-LMA, Inc. Tenth Anniversary Meeting and Brochure, June 10, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - D-LMA, Inc. "Third Report" - Presentation, May 23, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - BID - Mission and Proposed Agenda and Services, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Photographs, 2
    - Aerials (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Aerials (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Aerials (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Aerials (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Aerials (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Battery Park (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Beekman Downtown Hospital (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Bowling Green Park (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Brooklyn Bridge (and Redevelopment Areas) (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Brooklyn Bridge (and Redevelopment Areas) (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Buildings - Banker's Trust Building (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Buildings - Baxter and Walker Streets (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Buildings - One Battery Park Plaza (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Buildings - Battery Park Plaza (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Buildings - 55 Broad Street (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Buildings - 140 Broadway (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Buildings - 140 Broadway - Excavation, June 1965 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Buildings - 220 Broadway, Western Electric Building (Box 5, Folder 97)
    - Buildings - Chase Manhattan Bank (Box 5, Folder 98)
    - Buildings - Chatham Towers (Box 5, Folder 99)
    - Buildings - 100 Church Street (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - Buildings - 110-120 Church Street (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Buildings - City Hall (Box 5, Folder 102)
    - Buildings - Convention Center (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Buildings - Empire State Building (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Buildings - Family Court Building (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - Buildings - Federal Hall (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - Buildings - Federal Reserve Bank (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - Buildings - Foley Square (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Buildings - Franklin National Bank (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Buildings - General (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Buildings - Home Insurance Company (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Buildings - 127 John Street (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Buildings - 130 John Street (Box 6, Folder 113)
    - Buildings - New Buildings Completed 1950-1965 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Buildings - One New York Plaza, October 1969 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Buildings - One New York Plaza - Street Construction, October-November 1970 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Buildings - Four New York Plaza (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - Buildings - New York University - Graduate School of Business - Charles E. Merrill Hall (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - Buildings - Pace College (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Buildings - 20 Pine Street (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - Buildings - 80 Pine Street (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Buildings - 88 Pine Street (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Buildings - Seamen's Church Institute (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Buildings - Southbridge Towers (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Buildings - 24 State Street (Box 6, Folder 125)
    - Buildings - Trinity Church (Box 6, Folder 126)
    - Buildings - U.S. Custom House (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Buildings - 100 Wall Street (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Buildings - 110 Wall Street (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Buildings - 90 Washington Street (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Buildings - 90 William Street (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - Buildings - 100 William Street (Box 6, Folder 132)
    - Buildings - World Trade Center (Box 6, Folder 133)
    - Buildings - World Trade Center (Box 6, Folder 134)
    - Buildings - World Trade Center (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Civic Center (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Construction (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Governor's Island, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Heliport (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - IDEA, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 140)
    - Lower Manhattan Cultural Council (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - Maps, Models, Proposals, Reports (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Manhattan Landing (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - MEDphone Corporation (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 145)
    - Nassau Street Mall (Box 7, Folder 146)
    - New York Cocoa Exchange, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 147)
    - New York World's Fair, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - Portraits - John D. Butt (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - Portraits - Barbara L. Christen (Box 7, Folder 150)
    - Portraits - David Dinkins (Box 7, Folder 151)
    - Portraits - Robert Douglass (Box 7, Folder 152)
    - Portraits - Samuel Ehrenhalt (Box 7, Folder 153)
    - Portraits - Alan R. Griffith (Box 7, Folder 154)
    - Portraits - Salley Hernandez-Pinero (Box 7, Folder 155)
    - Portraits - Con Howe (Box 7, Folder 156)
    - Portraits - Rudi Rinaldi (Box 7, Folder 157)
    - Portraits - David Rockefeller (Box 7, Folder 158)
    - Portraits - Rosemary Scanlon (Box 7, Folder 159)
    - Portraits - Barry Sullivan (Box 7, Folder 160)
    - Portraits - Peter Vallone (Box 7, Folder 161)
    - Portraits - John Zuccuotti (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - Portraits - Downtown People (Unidentified) (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - South Street Seaport - Wavertree (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - Streets - Fulton and South Streets (Box 8, Folder 165)
    - Streets - General (Box 8, Folder 166)
    - Streets - Lower Manhattan Expressway (Box 8, Folder 167)
    - Streets - Traffic Ban (Box 8, Folder 168)
    - Streets - Wall Street and Financial District (Box 8, Folder 169)
    - Streets - Water Street (Box 8, Folder 170)
    - Subways (Box 8, Folder 171)
    - Verrazano-Narrows Bridge, May 1963 (Box 8, Folder 172)
    - Waterfront (including South Street Seaport) (Box 8, Folder 173)
    - Oversized Photograph - Pace College (Box 9, Folder 174)
    - Oversized Photographs - World Trade Center (Box 9, Folder 175)
    - Oversized Photograph - Unidentified (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - Slides, 3
    - Aerials (Box 10, Folder 177)
    - Aerials, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 178)
    - Battery Park City, 1966 (and undated) (Box 10, Folder 179)
    - Brooklyn Bridge (and Redevelopment Areas) (Box 10, Folder 180)
    - Brooklyn Bridge Southwest, March 17, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 181)
    - Brooklyn Bridge Southwest - Demolition, October 1967 (Box 10, Folder 182)
    - Buildings - Atlas-McGrath Building (Box 10, Folder 183)
    - Buildings - Banker's Trust Building (Box 10, Folder 184)
    - Buildings - One Battery Park Plaza (Box 10, Folder 185)
    - Buildings - 17 Battery Place North (Box 10, Folder 186)
    - Buildings - 55 Broad Street (Box 10, Folder 187)
    - Buildings - 140 Broadway (Box 10, Folder 188)
    - Buildings - Chase Manhattan Bank (Box 10, Folder 189)
    - Buildings - Chatham Green and Chatham Towers (Box 10, Folder 190)
    - Buildings - City Hall (Box 11, Folder 191)
    - Buildings - 22 Cortlandt Street (Box 11, Folder 192)
    - Buildings - Family Court Building (Box 11, Folder 193)
    - Buildings - Federal Building/Foley Square (Box 11, Folder 194)
    - Buildings - Federal Building, March 15 and April 2, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 195)
    - Buildings - Federal Building, Late August/Early September 1965 (Box 11, Folder 196)
    - Buildings - Federal Building, June 1966 (Box 11, Folder 197)
    - Buildings - Federal Reserve Bank (Box 11, Folder 198)
    - Buildings - Franklin Bank Building (Box 11, Folder 199)
    - Buildings - Fraunces Tavern Block (Box 11, Folder 200)
    - Buildings - General (Box 11, Folder 201)
    - Buildings - 10 Hanover Square (Box 11, Folder 202)
    - Buildings - Home Improvement Building (Box 11, Folder 203)
    - Buildings - 127 and 130 John Street (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - Buildings - New York Stock Exchange (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - Buildings - New York Telephone Company (Broadway building) (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - Buildings - One New York Plaza (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - Buildings - 2 New York Plaza (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - Buildings - 4 New York Plaza (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - Buildings - 20 Pine Street (Chemical Bank) (Box 12, Folder 210)
    - Buildings - 70 Pine Street (Cities Service Tower) (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - Buildings - Police Headquarters (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - Buildings - One State Street Plaza (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - Buildings - Southbridge Towers (Box 12, Folder 214)
    - Buildings - Trinity Church (and St. Paul's Chapel) (Box 12, Folder 215)
    - Buildings - 110 Wall Street (Box 12, Folder 216)
    - Buildings - 90 Washington Street, July 1967 (Box 13, Folder 217)
    - Buildings - 90 William Street (Box 13, Folder 218)
    - Buildings - 100 William Street (Box 13, Folder 219)
    - Buildings - Woolworth Building (Box 13, Folder 220)
    - Buildings - World Trade Center (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - Civic Center (Box 13, Folder 222)
    - Construction - General (Box 13, Folder 223)
    - Convention Center (Box 13, Folder 224)
    - Downtown, October 1968 (Box 13, Folder 225)
    - Ellis Island (Box 13, Folder 226)
    - John B. Goodman - ITE Speech (Box 13, Folder 227)
    - Heliport (Box 14, Folder 228)
    - Landmarks (Box 14, Folder 229)
    - Maps, Models, Proposals, Reports (Box 14, Folder 230)
    - Metro City (Box 14, Folder 231)
    - Pace College (Box 14, Folder 232)
    - Parks and Pedestrians (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - People Movers (Box 14, Folder 234)
    - Slide Presentation - E. F. Wagner (Box 14, Folder 235)
    - Slide Presentation - E. F. Wagner (Box 14, Folder 236)
    - Staggered Work Hours (Box 14, Folder 237)
    - Statue of Liberty (Box 14, Folder 238)
    - Streets - Beaver (Northeast corner) and Broad (Box 15, Folder 239)
    - Streets - Broadway at Wall Street, 8:45 AM, March 1963 (Box 15, Folder 240)
    - Streets - Fulton Street (Box 15, Folder 241)
    - Streets - General (Box 15, Folder 242)
    - Streets - Lower Manhattan Expressway (Box 15, Folder 243)
    - Streets - Nassau Street at Maiden Lane (Box 15, Folder 244)
    - Streets - Wall Street Financial District (Box 15, Folder 245)
    - Streets - Wall at William Street, 9:00 AM, March 1963 (Box 15, Folder 246)
    - Streets - Water Street (Box 15, Folder 247)
    - Subways (Box 15, Folder 248)
    - Waterfront (including South Street Seaport) (Box 15, Folder 249)
  - Audio and Visual Materials, 4
    - Lower Manhattan Demolition and New Buildings, July-October 1968 (Box 16, Folder 250)
    - Lower Manhattan Demolition and New Buildings, July-October 1968 (Box 16, Folder 0250A)
    - Sound Recording - Presentation at 15th Anniversary of D-LMA, June 7, 1973, 4PM (Box 16, Folder 251)
    - Sound Recording on Compact Disc - Presentation at 15th Anniversary of D-LMA, June 7, 1973, 4PM (Box 16, Folder 0251A)
    - Sound Recording - "The People Problem" - WBZ Radio Program, No date (Box 16, Folder 252)
    - "Lower Manhattan" [VHS] [a Cresta video souvenir] (Box 16, Folder 253)